<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>History of Economic Thought on Home</title>
    <link>https://tudorschlanger.com/tags/history-of-economic-thought/</link>
    <description>Recent content in History of Economic Thought on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2021. All rights reserved. The views expressed on this website are solely my own.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tudorschlanger.com/tags/history-of-economic-thought/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Economics Became a Mathematical Science (II)</title>
      <link>https://tudorschlanger.com/blog/econ-became-mathy-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tudorschlanger.com/blog/econ-became-mathy-ii/</guid>
      <description>In the previous entry, I ended on the birth of a new era for both mathematics and an incipient branch of economics, namely mathematical economics. Both born out of Hilbert’s Formalist Program, both seeking purity and clarity above all, and in so doing, both inching away from worldly concerns. Before I proceed the inquiry into how the then-germinating strand of economics now claims so much of the methodological space of the discipline, I want to provide some background of the 30s and 40s landscape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Economics Became a Mathematical Science (I)</title>
      <link>https://tudorschlanger.com/blog/econ-became-mathy-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tudorschlanger.com/blog/econ-became-mathy-i/</guid>
      <description>I have recently taken an interest into the history of economic thought. And in particular, I started pondering over the development of Economics into the mathematical social science it is today. The word mathematical is front and center here, because Economics – unlike other disciplines such as sociology, anthropology or political studies – makes a claim that it can use its rigorous, mathematical framework to study the fundamental forces underprining the economy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
