<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>climate change on Home</title>
    <link>https://tudorschlanger.com/tags/climate-change/</link>
    <description>Recent content in climate change on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2020. All rights reserved. The views expressed on this website are solely my own. No responsibility for them should be attributed to the Bank of Canada.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tudorschlanger.com/tags/climate-change/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Choice, Discount Rates, and Climate Change Action</title>
      <link>https://tudorschlanger.com/blog/discount-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tudorschlanger.com/blog/discount-rate/</guid>
      <description>In the previous episode …In my previous post, I was emphasizing that the time period matters when considering to internalize a certain externality. In the perpetual cost-benefit analysis that people make between present and future, people put a higher emphasis on the benefits accruing in the present and a lesser emphasis on future costs. For this reason, people can easily coalesce in favour of limiting the damage of the Covid-19 virus, but can fail to do so against a more distant threat such as climate change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19, Climate Change and the Tragedy of Horizons</title>
      <link>https://tudorschlanger.com/blog/tragedy-of-horizons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tudorschlanger.com/blog/tragedy-of-horizons/</guid>
      <description>In the previous episode …In my previous post, I was arguing that the current containment measures are not only a safeguard of human lives but also of longer term economic prosperity. They prevent us from making short-sighted gains at the price of our safety and the economy’s future productive capacity. In a nutshell, containment measures allow us to internalize the virus externality that arises from our economic activity and improve social welfare overall.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
